Gaurav Jaiswal

Allahabad, Uttar Pradesh gauravjaiswal97_zzk@indeedemail.com 9935016467

An Electrical Engineer with 4 years of extensive experience in handling electrical equipment installation for commercial and hospital projects and maintenance of electrical equipments, seeking a challenging role with a reputed organization to contribute accrued expertise in formulating organizational profit objectives.

JOB PROFILE

- > Maintenance and troubleshooting of Electrical System Equipment (LT Panel / HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer / Motors / UPS / PLC / STP / Fire Fighting System / Fire Alarm system / CCTV etc).
- > Erection and Commissioning of Electrical Equipment (LT Panel / HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer / UPS / Cable Laying / Cable Tray etc. works).
- > Review and Coordinate Design, Drawings, BOQ, and Shop Drawings to ensure compliance with client requirements & Safety norms.
- > Preparing Work program schedules, Material acquisition plan, Inspection and testing, resolving technical situation in a timely manner for smooth execution of the project
- > Monitor site progress and lead the team to ensure proper implementation on site in compliance with Project schedule, Quality Standards, Electrical codes, and Medical regulations
- > Studying Work schedule and issue drawings for preparing work plan.
- > Carrying out site execution job maintaining relevant IS standards and relevant Safety norms.
- > Preparing daily work plan & progress reports to meet client's requirements.
- > MOM Minutes of Meeting with Client and Consultant (client Engineer & P.W.D Engineers).
- > Billing, Measurement Sheet & Reconciliation work after completion of the project.
- > Deliver completed projects on time and within budget maintaining relevant IS standards, Quality and Safety norms.
- > Monitor and review monthly progress reports.
- > Industrial Automation (PLC, SCADA, DCS, HMI & Drives).
- > AutoCAD 2016.

Work Experience

Junior Engineer (Electrical Maintenance)

BECIL Noida, Posted At - Land Ports Authority of India, Integrated Check Post - Jogbani, Bihar February 2019 to December 2019

Jogbani Bihar (Under Ministry of Home Affairs) (A Government of India Enterprise).

Designation: Junior Engineer (Electrical Maintenance).

Duration: From 15 Feb. 2019 to 31 Dec. 2019.

Responsibility: Maintenance of Electrical System Equipment (LT Panel / HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer / Motor / UPS / PLC / STP / Fire Fighting System / Fire Alarm System / CCTV System / Cables etc) & monitoring of on-going project work at site.

(2) Company: - Mishrilal Associates Pvt. Ltd. Bareilly (U.P.)

Mishrilal Associates Pvt. Ltd. was established in 2011 is an infrastructure company specialized in the field of Rural Electrification, Distribution & Transmission network and engaged in the construction on 33/11 KV, 132/33 KV power sub-stations and other products such as PCC Poles, Conductors and Transformers through its sister concerns.

Billing Engineer

DDUGJY - Moradabad, Uttar Pradesh November 2018 to February 2019

3) Company: - Sachin Electricals Pvt. Ltd., Sahibabad, Ghaziabad (U.P.)

Sachin Electricals Pvt. Ltd. are 'A' class electrical contractors involve in offering service in the field of supplying, installation, testing and commissioning of electrical projects. Our range includes Substation installation (up to 66 KV), overhead HT/ LT transmission lines installation, HT & LT cable laying, internal/ external wiring, internal/ external lighting, LT distribution systems, communication systems, fire protection systems, instrumentation/automation systems, Plant and Machinery, DG sets, Installation & testing of Panels.

Tertiary Health Care Super Specialist Hospital Project

Up-gradation of Darbhanga Medical College & Hospital - Darbhanga, Bihar April 2017 to November 2017

Darbhanga, Bihar - Under Pradhan Mantri Swasthya Suraksha Yojana, Phase iii).

Client:- HLL Infra Tech Services Ltd (HITES) - Subsidiary of HLL Life Care Ltd (A Government of India Enterprises).

Work:- Supply, Installation, Testing Commissioning of Internal and external electrification work including 11 kV substation work. (Installation, Testing, Inspection /Troubleshooting of Electrical systems - LT Panel /HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer/UPS/Underground Cable Laying/Cable Tray etc). Designation: Site Incharge (Duration: April 2017 to 22 Nov. 2017).

Project 2:- Tertiary Health Care Super Specialist Hospital Project, Falakata, Alipurduar, West Bengal.

Site In-charge

July 2014 to November 2017

PROJECT HANDLED

Sr. Engineer

VLCC Personal Care Ltd - Goalpara, Assam February 2017 to April 2017

Goalpara, Assam (Industrial Project).

Work: Erection & Commissioning of Internal and external electrification work. (LT Panel / HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer).

Designation: Sr. Engineer (Duration: 25 Feb. 2017 to 2 April 2017).

Sr. Engineer

North Bengal Medical College - Shiliguri, West Bengal December 2016 to April 2017

Siliguri, West Bengal.

Contractor:- Gannon Dunkerley Co. Ltd. (GDCL)

Main Client:- HSCC (India) Ltd. (A Government of India Enterprise)

Work: Supply, Installation, Testing Commissioning of Internal and external electrification work including 11 kV substation work. (Installation, Testing, Inspection /Troubleshooting of Electrical

systems - LT Panel / HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer / UPS etc.)
Designation: Sr. Engineer (Duration: 4 Dec. 2016 to 25 April. 2017).

Assistant Engineer

Bridge and Roof Co. (India) Ltd May 2016 to April 2017

Work: Supply, Installation, Testing Commissioning of Internal and external electrification work including 11 kV substation work. (Installation, Testing, Inspection /Troubleshooting of Electrical systems - LT Panel / HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer/UPS etc.)

Designation: Assistant Engineer (Duration: 15 May 2016 to 25 April 2017).

Assistant Engineer

Bridge and Roof Co. (India) Ltd - Bankura, West Bengal May 2015 to March 2016

A Government of India Enterprise).

Work: Supply, Installation, Testing Commissioning of Internal and external electrification work including 11 kV substation work. (Installation, Testing, Inspection /Troubleshooting of Electrical systems - LT Panel / HT Panel / D.G Set / Transformer / UPS etc.)

Designation: Assistant Engineer (Duration: 5 May 2015 to 15 March 2016).

Trainee Engineer

Sterling & Wilson Limited - Bawal, Haryana July 2014 to May 2015

Main Client:- Haryana State Industrial and Infrastructure Development Corporation Limited Work:- Erection of 220/132/33 Sub Station at Bawal, Haryana.

Designation: Trainee Engineer (Duration: 1 July 2014 to 4 May 2015).

TRAINING AT SOFCON INDIA PVT LTD NOIDA

- PLC's: (Micrologix 1000-1200, SLC-503, Siemens-200, 300) Ladder Logic Development, Wiring & Troubleshooting.
- SCADA: Wonderware (Intouch), RS View 32 Applications & Development.
- Process Instrumentation: RTDS, Thermocouples, Level Sensor, Flow sensor Proximity Sensors, Relays, Contactors, Thermal overload relays.
- Motors/ Starters/ Control Circuits: Induction Motors, Torque/ Speed characteristics, Star Delta Starters, DOL Starters, Reversing starters, interlocking circuits, panel Wiring.
- HMI (Panel View 300 Micro) Creating Applications, Downloading / Uploading Program, Communication with PLC HMI.

DRIVE:

- VFD Principle of operation and applications.
- Operation and program parameters by keypad mode.
- Operation and program parameters by remote mode (start stop, potentiometer).
- Communication with PLC (wiring diagram) controlling with start stop.

- Communication with PLC and controlling with SCADA Software.
- Designing of drive control panel.
- Fault Finding / troubleshooting in AC Drive.

Education

B.Tech in Dr. A.P.J Abdul

University / Board - Kalam, Maharashtra 2014

Electrical & Electronics

Technical University - Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

Skills / IT Skills

Electrical equipment erection and Commissioning, Electrical equipment erection and Commissioning